PULAK KAR

Thakurpara, Cumilla

Pulak_kar portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/

pulakkar@stud.cou.ac.bd (+88) 015 21 30 18 84

Hello there! I'm a Professional Front-end and Back-end Developer Expert. I have also completed my **B.Sc** in Computer Science and Information Systems. I've taken many (Modern Web Design and front-end and Back-end Web Development) lessons from famous institutions. My educational background helped me a lot to thrive in this career. I have created many fabulous and eye-catching websites, including Portfolio, Corporate, Development Tax, Blog / Magazine, Retail, Security Management, Education, Real estate, e-commerce, etc. My specialty is I can handle any **project**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laravel Developer at Mysoftheaven (BD) LTD. Dhaka, Bangladesh. Jul 2023 - Present

- Spearheading the development of web applications using the Laravel framework, I contribute to the entire software development lifecycle from conception to deployment.
- Working closely with front-end developers, I ensure smooth integration of user interfaces with server-side logic, delivering cohesive and feature-rich applications.
- I proactively troubleshoot and debug issues, optimizing performance and user experience for our applications.

Communication Officer at Shikhbeshobai IT Limited, Dhaka Aug 2022 - Apr 2023

- Maintained a database of media organizations and contacts within them.
- Regularly meet with and conduct interviews with media personnel.
- Create and produce internal newsletters for the organization.

Front-end Developer at Startup Cumilla, Cumilla Jan 2019 - Apr 2022

- Developed websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

PROJECTS & LIVE

• Developed an E-commerce website (G-Tech):

- 1. Collaborated with internal marketing team and a small team of developers to build custom websites.
- 2. Asist team members with various problem-solving.
- 3. Build responsive websites and apply modern techniques.

• Working on a class Diabetes Prediction using Machine Learning system using Python:

- 1. Installing Libraries (imported most common libraries used in python for machine learning such as Pandas, Seaborn, Matplitlib etc)
- 2. Importing Data, Missing Value, Analysis Exploratory (anlytics using GUI), Data Analysis Feature Engineering

- An innovative idea on renewable power & energy to take part in this national competition (Bicchuron):
 - 1. Entrepreneurship and development of entrepreneurial ecosystem with resources and creating connections with a local and global network for sustainable development.
 - 2. Web design & development, Information Technology, ICT focuses on communication.

GITHUB LIVE PROJECT:

1. Portfolio: https://hro57.github.io/Pulak kar portfolio/

2. Land Security Management: http://devlsgportal.mysoftheaven.com/

3. Land Development Tax: http://stageldtax-portal.mysoftheaven.com/

4. Panda E-commerce: https://hro57.github.io/pandda-ecommerce-bootstrap/

5. Donate: https://hro57.github.io/donate-now/

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

• Full Stack Software Developer Php & Laravel | JavaScript | React JS | Node JS | MySql | API | Tailwind | Bootstrap | GitHub

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Engineering (Information & Communication System)
Comilla University
2016 – 2021
3.06(Out of 4.00)

Higher Secondary School
Comilla Government College, Cumilla.
2014 – 2016
4.17(Out of 5.00)

Secondary School Certificate Comilla Zilla School, Cumilla 2008-2013 5.00(Out of 5.00)

REFERENCE

Name: Md. Tofeal Ahmed

Position: Associate Professor

Institution: Comilla University

Phone: +8801717671744

Email: tofael ice ru@yahoo.com